{"Questions":[{"CategoryID":10,"Category":"Alice and Bob","Question":"These two commonly used names in cryptography represent the sender and receiver of a message in examples of numerous cryptographic protocols.","Answer":"Who are Alice and Bob?","Value":200,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":10,"Category":"Alice and Bob","Question":"They are the world's most famous cryptography couple.","Answer":"Who are Alice and Bob?","Value":200,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":10,"Category":"Alice and Bob","Question":"Alice and Bob want to establish a secure communication channel, so they use this public key exchange protocol to agree on a large prime number, P, and a base G to produce a secret keys as well as a shared secret","Answer":"What is Diffie-Hellman key exchange?","Value":200,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":10,"Category":"Alice and Bob","Question":"Alice and Bob are both involved in this blockchain network where blocks are published once every 10 minutes.","Answer":"What is the Bitcoin Network?","Value":400,"Source":"Kohler, C. (2022, November 23). What is bitcoin block time? The Bitcoin Manual. https:\/\/thebitcoinmanual.com\/articles\/btc-block-time\/"},{"CategoryID":10,"Category":"Alice and Bob","Question":"Alice and Bob want to use this type of agreement algorithm to ensure that data stored in a blockchain network is legitimate to avoid double spending.","Answer":"What is a consensus algorithm?","Value":400,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":10,"Category":"Alice and Bob","Question":"Alice wants to send Bob some Bitcoin, the transaction between them would be stored on this type of ledger.","Answer":"What is a distributed ledger?","Value":600,"Source":"Collomb, A., & Sok, K. (2016). Blockchain\/distributed ledger technology (DLT): What impact on the financial sector?. Digiworld Economic Journal, (103)."},{"CategoryID":10,"Category":"Alice and Bob","Question":"Alice, Bob, and Carl would like to be apart of this collective that makes decision-making decentralized and fair to all those who are apart of it. ","Answer":"What is a Decentralized Autonomous Organization?","Value":600,"Source":"Jentzsch, C. (2016). Decentralized autonomous organization to automate governance. White paper, November."},{"CategoryID":10,"Category":"Alice and Bob","Question":"This security measure was inspired from the Alice and Bob problem.","Answer":"What is SSL\/TLS Handshake?","Value":600,"Source":"Prabhu, M. (2020, May 19). How alice begins talking to bob: The ssl\/tls handshake. Medium. https:\/\/medium.com\/@manish.prabhu\/how-alice-begins-talking-to-bob-the-ssl-tls-handshake-56faa88e62e1"},{"CategoryID":10,"Category":"Alice and Bob","Question":"Alice recently purchased this Non-Fungible Token for an all time record of $91.8 million dollars.","Answer":"What is Merge?","Value":800,"Source":"The most expensive nfts ever sold. Crypto.com: The best place to buy Bitcoin, Ethereum, and 250+ altcoins. (2023, January 4). Retrieved January 29, 2023, from https:\/\/crypto.com\/university\/most-expensive-nfts#:~:text=1.,Merge%20%E2%80%94%20US%2491.8M&amp;text=Digital%20artist%20Pak's%20creation%20Merge,sold%20by%20a%20living%20artist. "},{"CategoryID":10,"Category":"Alice and Bob","Question":"Alice and Bob are legitimate users in a blockchain network who want to make a transaction. Eve is a malicious user who wants to carry out this type of attack that creates multiple fake identities that can manipulate the consensus algorithms of the blockchain network.","Answer":"What is the Sybil Attack?","Value":800,"Source":"Syed, T. A., Alzahrani, A., Jan, S., Siddiqui, M. S., Nadeem, A., & Alghamdi, T. (2019). A comparative analysis of blockchain architecture and its applications: Problems and recommendations. IEEE access, 7, 176838-176869."},{"CategoryID":10,"Category":"Alice and Bob","Question":"Bob wants to use a decentralized application on the Ethereum network which requires this type of payment that provides incentives to validators in the network","Answer":"What are gas fees?","Value":1000,"Source":"Syed, T. A., Alzahrani, A., Jan, S., Siddiqui, M. S., Nadeem, A., & Alghamdi, T. (2019). A comparative analysis of blockchain architecture and its applications: Problems and recommendations. IEEE access, 7, 176838-176869."},{"CategoryID":10,"Category":"Alice and Bob","Question":"Alice wants to send Bob some digital currency. Eve, who controls a large part of the network, sees this an opportunity to perform this attack where she sends the digital currency to Bob and another to send the same currency to herself.","Answer":"What is Double Spending?","Value":1000,"Source":"Syed, T. A., Alzahrani, A., Jan, S., Siddiqui, M. S., Nadeem, A., & Alghamdi, T. (2019). A comparative analysis of blockchain architecture and its applications: Problems and recommendations. IEEE access, 7, 176838-176869."},{"CategoryID":13,"Category":"Availability","Question":"These 2 D's make it less likely that the blockchain will become unavailable due to the failure of a single node.","Answer":"What is decentralized and distributed?","Value":200,"Source":"Weber et al. (2017) \"On Availability for Blockchain-Based Systems,\" 2017 IEEE 36th Symposium on Reliable Distributed Systems (SRDS), Hong Kong, China, 2017, pp. 64-73, doi: 10.1109\/SRDS.2017.15."},{"CategoryID":13,"Category":"Availability","Question":"This type of data is directly stored on a blockchain network across distributed nodes to ensure tamper-resistance.","Answer":"What is on-chain data?","Value":400,"Source":"@wackerow, @AlehNat (2022) DATA AVAILABILITY. https:\/\/ethereum.org\/en\/developers\/docs\/data-availability\/"},{"CategoryID":13,"Category":"Availability","Question":"This type of data can be stored in centralized databases or other systems, in order to supplement data stored on the blockchain.","Answer":"What is off-chain data?","Value":400,"Source":"@wackerow, @AlehNat (2022) DATA AVAILABILITY. https:\/\/ethereum.org\/en\/developers\/docs\/data-availability\/"},{"CategoryID":13,"Category":"Availability","Question":"The function allows blockchain nodes to verify that data for a proposed block is available without having to download the entire block.","Answer":"What is data availability sampling?","Value":400,"Source":"@wackerow, @AlehNat (2022) DATA AVAILABILITY. https:\/\/ethereum.org\/en\/developers\/docs\/data-availability\/"},{"CategoryID":13,"Category":"Availability","Question":"This type of blockchain restricts data to predetermined users, configurations, and programming. ","Answer":"What is a private blockchain?","Value":600,"Source":"Guidi, B. and Michienzi, A. (2020) \"Users and Bots behaviour analysis in Blockchain Social Media,\" 2020 Seventh International Conference on Social Networks Analysis, Management and Security (SNAMS), Paris, France, 2020, pp. 1-8, doi: 10.1109\/SNAMS52053.2020.9336553."},{"CategoryID":13,"Category":"Availability","Question":"Opposite of centralized, server-client architecture and is the foundation of blockchain technology.","Answer":"What is Peer-to-peer technology?","Value":600,"Source":"Acharjamayum, R. Patgiri and D. Devi (2018) \"Blockchain: A Tale of Peer to Peer Security,\" 2018 IEEE Symposium Series on Computational Intelligence (SSCI), Bangalore, India, 2018, pp. 609-617, doi: 10.1109\/SSCI.2018.8628826."},{"CategoryID":13,"Category":"Availability","Question":"This node downloads and checks that every transaction in the blockchain is valid.","Answer":"What is a full node?","Value":800,"Source":"Al-Bassam, M. (2020) What Is Data Availability? https:\/\/coinmarketcap.com\/alexandria\/article\/what-is-data-availability"},{"CategoryID":13,"Category":"Availability","Question":"A critical process of blockchain, this is important to increase redundancy among nodes in the case a critical failure may occur.","Answer":"What is Replication?","Value":800,"Source":"Ruoti, S., Kaiser, B., Yerukhimovich, A., Clark, J., & Cunningham, R. (2019). Blockchain technology: what is it good for?.\u00a0Communications of the ACM,\u00a063(1), 46-53."},{"CategoryID":13,"Category":"Availability","Question":"This technique is used to divide a blockchain network into smaller smarts, which are then mamaneged and processed by different nodes in the network.","Answer":"What is Sharding?","Value":1000,"Source":"Al-Bassam, M. (2020) What Is Data Availability? https:\/\/coinmarketcap.com\/alexandria\/article\/what-is-data-availability"},{"CategoryID":13,"Category":"Availability","Question":"These pieces of data can be used to provide additional data protection and ensure that the blockchain remains available, even in the event of corruption","Answer":"What are errasure codes?","Value":1000,"Source":"Al-Bassam, M. (2020) What Is Data Availability? https:\/\/coinmarketcap.com\/alexandria\/article\/what-is-data-availability"},{"CategoryID":11,"Category":"Confidentiality","Question":"This process allows for the conversion of a plain text into an unreadable format using a key","Answer":"What is Encryption?","Value":200,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":11,"Category":"Confidentiality","Question":"This process allows for the conversion of a ciphertext back to its plaintext form","Answer":"What is Decryption?","Value":200,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":11,"Category":"Confidentiality","Question":"This cryptocurrency asset uses AES encryption standards to encrypt private keys in their wallers in order to maintain classified information confidential","Answer":"What is Bitcoin?","Value":400,"Source":"How Bitcoin Uses Cryptography | River Learn - Bitcoin Technology. (n.d.). River Financial. https:\/\/river.com\/learn\/how-bitcoin-uses-cryptography\/\n\n\u200c"},{"CategoryID":11,"Category":"Confidentiality","Question":"It is a method in Blockchain technology that separates confidential or confidential information into smaller components and transmits them to network users. ","Answer":"What is secret sharing?","Value":400,"Source":"Raman, R. K. and Varshney, L. R.  (2018) \"Distributed Storage Meets Secret Sharing on the Blockchain,\" 2018 Information Theory and Applications Workshop (ITA), San Diego, CA, USA, 2018, pp. 1-6, doi: 10.1109\/ITA.2018.8503089."},{"CategoryID":11,"Category":"Confidentiality","Question":"This type of blockchain is closed, not publically accessible, and often has an access control layer.","Answer":"What is a permissioned blockchain?","Value":600,"Source":"Knirsch, F., Unterweger, A., & Engel, D. (2019). Implementing a blockchain from scratch: why, how, and what we learned. EURASIP Journal on Information Security, 2019, 1-14."},{"CategoryID":11,"Category":"Confidentiality","Question":"The cryptography behind the protocol is based on it where the 'key' for encrypting a message or transaction is different from the 'key' to decrypt it. ","Answer":"What is asymmetric encryption?","Value":600,"Source":"Apte, S., Petrovsky, N. (2016) Will blockchain technology revolutionize excipient supply chain management? Editorial Board, Journal of Excipients and Food Chemicals 7 (3)."},{"CategoryID":11,"Category":"Confidentiality","Question":"This service in blockchain technology helps obscure the source of a transaction by combining it with others.","Answer":"What is a Mixing Service?","Value":800,"Source":"Henry, R., Herzberg, A., & Kate, A. (2018). Blockchain access privacy: Challenges and directions. IEEE Security & Privacy, 16(4), 38-45."},{"CategoryID":11,"Category":"Confidentiality","Question":"For each new document, the creator attaches it to attest the document\u2019s compliance. Instead of evaluating a given document rule, the corresponding smart contract function only checks the validity of the proof.","Answer":"What is zero-knowledge proof?","Value":800,"Source":"Fatz, F., Hake, P. and Fettke, P. (2020) \"Confidentiality-preserving Validation of Tax Documents on the Blockchain.\" Wirtschaftsinformatik (Zentrale Tracks)"},{"CategoryID":11,"Category":"Confidentiality","Question":"This kind of signature can be used in a private blockchain to allow a participant to digitally sign a transaction on behalf of a group if the signer has knowledge of some secret information.","Answer":"What is a Ring Signature?","Value":1000,"Source":"Mercer, R. (2016). Privacy on the blockchain: Unique ring signatures. arXiv preprint arXiv:1612.01188."},{"CategoryID":11,"Category":"Confidentiality","Question":"It ensures that all transaction amounts are hidden from public view using a commitment to the amount.","Answer":"What is a confidential transaction?","Value":1000,"Source":"Jivanyan, A.(2019) \"Lelantus: Towards Confidentiality and Anonymity of Blockchain Transactions from Standard Assumptions.\" IACR Cryptol. ePrint Arch. 2019: 373."},{"CategoryID":9,"Category":"Database or Blockchain?","Question":"A differene between a database and the majority of  block chains is that a block chain has this type of network. ","Answer":"What is decentralized?","Value":200,"Source":"Iredale, G. (2021, July 30). Blockchain vs database: Understanding the difference. 101 Blockchains. https:\/\/101blockchains.com\/blockchain-vs-database-the-difference\/"},{"CategoryID":9,"Category":"Database or Blockchain?","Question":"This is always a centralized ledger, run by an administrator","Answer":"What is a Database?","Value":200,"Source":"Iredale, G. (2021, July 30). Blockchain vs database: Understanding the difference. 101 Blockchains. https:\/\/101blockchains.com\/blockchain-vs-database-the-difference\/"},{"CategoryID":9,"Category":"Database or Blockchain?","Question":"This type of block chain is similar to a database in that it may have a centralized aspect or approach.","Answer":"What is a private blockchain?","Value":400,"Source":"Iredale, G. (2021, July 30). Blockchain vs database: Understanding the difference. 101 Blockchains. https:\/\/101blockchains.com\/blockchain-vs-database-the-difference\/"},{"CategoryID":9,"Category":"Database or Blockchain?","Question":"This is the most common type of blockchain used by private organizations. ","Answer":"What is a Federated blockchain?","Value":400,"Source":"Iredale, G. (2021, July 30). Blockchain vs database: Understanding the difference. 101 Blockchains. https:\/\/101blockchains.com\/blockchain-vs-database-the-difference\/"},{"CategoryID":9,"Category":"Database or Blockchain?","Question":"A database supports CRUD that is an acroynym for this terminolgy. ","Answer":"What is Create, Read, Update and Delete?","Value":600,"Source":"Iredale, G. (2021, July 30). Blockchain vs database: Understanding the difference. 101 Blockchains. https:\/\/101blockchains.com\/blockchain-vs-database-the-difference\/"},{"CategoryID":9,"Category":"Database or Blockchain?","Question":"A blockchain consesus algorithum that is more effiecent and less power-hungry than POW. ","Answer":"What is PoS?","Value":600,"Source":"M. J. M. Chowdhury, A. Colman, M. A. Kabir, J. Han and P. Sarda, \"Blockchain Versus Database: A Critical Analysis,\" 2018 17th IEEE International Conference On Trust, Security And Privacy In Computing And Communications\/ 12th IEEE International Conference On Big Data Science And Engineering (TrustCom\/BigDataSE), New York, NY, USA, 2018, pp. 1348-1353, doi: 10.1109\/TrustCom\/BigDataSE.2018.00186."},{"CategoryID":9,"Category":"Database or Blockchain?","Question":"A peer-to-peer network that establishes these two important things to its users. ","Answer":"What is transparency and Trust?","Value":800,"Source":"M. J. M. Chowdhury, A. Colman, M. A. Kabir, J. Han and P. Sarda, \"Blockchain Versus Database: A Critical Analysis,\" 2018 17th IEEE International Conference On Trust, Security And Privacy In Computing And Communications\/ 12th IEEE International Conference On Big Data Science And Engineering (TrustCom\/BigDataSE), New York, NY, USA, 2018, pp. 1348-1353, doi: 10.1109\/TrustCom\/BigDataSE.2018.00186."},{"CategoryID":9,"Category":"Database or Blockchain?","Question":"This can cause a significant performance delay in a blockchain network when transactions verifications are pending. ","Answer":"What is a soft fork?","Value":800,"Source":"M. J. M. Chowdhury, A. Colman, M. A. Kabir, J. Han and P. Sarda, \"Blockchain Versus Database: A Critical Analysis,\" 2018 17th IEEE International Conference On Trust, Security And Privacy In Computing And Communications\/ 12th IEEE International Conference On Big Data Science And Engineering (TrustCom\/BigDataSE), New York, NY, USA, 2018, pp. 1348-1353, doi: 10.1109\/TrustCom\/BigDataSE.2018.00186."},{"CategoryID":9,"Category":"Database or Blockchain?","Question":"Block chain and DLT are used interchangeably in literature. Identify what this statement is addressing: \"A blockchain is just an example of a particular type of ledger, and there are other types of ledger. When a ledger (including a blockchain) is distributed across a network, it can be regarded as a Distributed Ledger. \"","Answer":"What is their difference?","Value":1000,"Source":"M. J. M. Chowdhury, A. Colman, M. A. Kabir, J. Han and P. Sarda, \"Blockchain Versus Database: A Critical Analysis,\" 2018 17th IEEE International Conference On Trust, Security And Privacy In Computing And Communications\/ 12th IEEE International Conference On Big Data Science And Engineering (TrustCom\/BigDataSE), New York, NY, USA, 2018, pp. 1348-1353, doi: 10.1109\/TrustCom\/BigDataSE.2018.00186."},{"CategoryID":9,"Category":"Database or Blockchain?","Question":"A database is more desirable for general purpose applications due to this complicated process in block chain. ","Answer":"What is Read and Write?","Value":1000,"Source":"W\u00fcst, K., & Gervais, A. (2018, June). Do you need a blockchain?. In\u00a02018 crypto valley conference on blockchain technology (CVCBT)\u00a0(pp. 45-54). IEEE."},{"CategoryID":8,"Category":"Digital Signatures","Question":"This is an electronic, encrypted, stamp of authentication on digital information","Answer":"What is a digital signature?","Value":200,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":8,"Category":"Digital Signatures","Question":"Digital signatures in blockchain systems use this type of  encryption technique. ","Answer":"What is asymmetric?","Value":200,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":8,"Category":"Digital Signatures","Question":"This digital signature algorithm is used in blockchain","Answer":"What is the Elliptic Curve Digital Signature Algorithm (ECDSA)?","Value":400,"Source":"McIsaac, B., Fohr, H. (2005) \"Legal Update, Canada: PIPEDA's Secure Electronic Signature Regulations Have Been\" Digital Evidence & Elec. Signature L. Rev. 71 "},{"CategoryID":8,"Category":"Digital Signatures","Question":"HR documents, commercial agreements, corporate documents such as instruments of transfer, consumer agreements are generally eligible for this use.  ","Answer":"What are electronic signatures?","Value":400,"Source":"McIsaac, B., Fohr, H. (2005) \"Legal Update, Canada: PIPEDA's Secure Electronic Signature Regulations Have Been\" Digital Evidence & Elec. Signature L. Rev. 71 "},{"CategoryID":8,"Category":"Digital Signatures","Question":"This Act defines the legal electronic signature requirements. ","Answer":"What is PIPEDA?","Value":600,"Source":"Lewis, M. (2002) Digital Signatures: Meeting the Traditional Requirements Electronically - A Canadian Perspective, 2 Asper REV. INT'l Bus. & TRADE L. 63"},{"CategoryID":8,"Category":"Digital Signatures","Question":"A Lack of efficiency  in this is a serious shortcoming of the Merkle tree signature scheme with a large number of possible signatures","Answer":"What is key generation?","Value":600,"Source":"Stubbs, R. (n.d.). Cryptographic key management concepts: On key generation, metadata, life-cycles, compromise and more. Retrieved 31 January 2023, from https:\/\/www.cryptomathic.com\/news-events\/blog\/cryptographic-key-management-concepts-on-key-generation-metadata-life-cycles-compromise-and-more"},{"CategoryID":8,"Category":"Digital Signatures","Question":"In addition to satisfying the general digital signature conditions, this type of signature must also satisfy the following two properties: \n1. The signer is invisible to the message he signed, namely the signer does not know the specific content of the message he signed.\n2. The signed message is not traceable, that is, when the signed message is published, the signer cannot know which one he signed.","Answer":"What is a blind signature?","Value":800,"Source":" W. Fang et al., \"Digital signature scheme for information non-repudiation in blockchain: a state-of-the-art review\", EURASIP Journal on Wireless Communications and Networking, 2020."},{"CategoryID":8,"Category":"Digital Signatures","Question":"The National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) Has Published this Federal Information Processing Standard, known as the Digital signature Standard (DSS)","Answer":"What is FIPS PUB 186?","Value":800,"Source":" W. Fang et al., \"Digital signature scheme for information non-repudiation in blockchain: a state-of-the-art review\", EURASIP Journal on Wireless Communications and Networking, 2020."},{"CategoryID":8,"Category":"Digital Signatures","Question":"Tian et al.  proposed a BVES based on traditional verifiable cryptographic signatures and blind signature ideas.  They built a fair and confidential contract signing agreement which not only allowed contract signers to complete fair contract signing through the blockchain, but also protected contract-related privacy content in this event. ` ","Answer":"What is the transaction being disclosed?","Value":1000,"Source":"S. B. Sadkhan and R. S. B. Sadkhan, \"Analysis of Different Types of Digital Signature,\"\u00a02022 8th International Engineering Conference on Sustainable Technology and Development (IEC), Erbil, Iraq, 2022, pp. 241-246, doi: 10.1109\/IEC54822.2022.9807502."},{"CategoryID":8,"Category":"Digital Signatures","Question":"Due to the inherent characteristics of the discrete logarithm problem, agents can forge the original signature to launch the security attacks, or replace the public key in this type of digital signature","Answer":"What is a Proxy Signature?","Value":1000,"Source":"S. B. Sadkhan and R. S. B. Sadkhan, \"Analysis of Different Types of Digital Signature,\"\u00a02022 8th International Engineering Conference on Sustainable Technology and Development (IEC), Erbil, Iraq, 2022, pp. 241-246, doi: 10.1109\/IEC54822.2022.9807502."},{"CategoryID":5,"Category":"Encryption and Decryption","Question":"This is the science of breaking cryptographically encrypted messages to recover their meaning. ","Answer":"What is Cryptanalysis?","Value":200,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":5,"Category":"Encryption and Decryption","Question":"A type of encryption that allows one party to prove they know a piece of information without revealing what it is.","Answer":"What is zero-knowledge encryption?","Value":200,"Source":"What does zero-knowledge mean? (n.d.). Nordlocker.com. Retrieved January 31, 2023, from https:\/\/nordlocker.com\/features\/zero-knowledge-encryption\/#:~:text=In%20encryption%2C%20zero-knowledge%20means"},{"CategoryID":5,"Category":"Encryption and Decryption","Question":"This type of proof allow for public verification off passwords without revealing the password. ","Answer":"What is a zero-knowledge password proof?","Value":400,"Source":"Bellare, M., Goldwasser, S. (1990). New Paradigms for Digital Signatures and Message Authentication Based on Non-Interactive Zero Knowledge Proofs. In: Brassard, G. (eds) Advances in Cryptology \u2014 CRYPTO\u2019 89 Proceedings. CRYPTO 1989. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol 435. Springer, New York, NY. https:\/\/doi.org\/10.1007\/0-387-34805-0_19"},{"CategoryID":5,"Category":"Encryption and Decryption","Question":"This encryption works by substituting each letter of the text or the written message  with another letter of the alphabet which is so many spaces or letters later in the alphabet","Answer":"What is the ceaser cipher?","Value":400,"Source":"Practical cryptography. (n.d.). Retrieved January 31, 2023, from http:\/\/practicalcryptography.com\/ciphers\/caesar-cipher\/"},{"CategoryID":5,"Category":"Encryption and Decryption","Question":"This technique allows a third party to decrypt a ciphertext without ever seeing the plaintext or the encryption key and it's mainly used in situations where a third party needs to decrypt the message without learning its contents.","Answer":"What is Blind Decryption?","Value":600,"Source":"Partala. (2017). Symmetric Blind Decryption with Perfect Secrecy. Journal of Computer Networks and Communications, 2017, 1\u201315. https:\/\/doi.org\/10.1155\/2017\/6575907"},{"CategoryID":5,"Category":"Encryption and Decryption","Question":"This type of encryption that uses random numbers to encrypt data, and encrypting the same plaintext with different numbers will produce different ciphertexts.","Answer":"What is Probabilistic Encryption?","Value":600,"Source":"Fontaine, C., & Galand, F. (2007). A survey of homomorphic encryption for nonspecialists. EURASIP Journal on Information Security, 2007, 1-10."},{"CategoryID":5,"Category":"Encryption and Decryption","Question":"This type of encryption that allows certain types of computations to be performed on ciphertext without the need to decrypt the data first, and it has the potential to enable a wide range of secure cloud-based services.","Answer":"What is Homomorphic Encryption?","Value":600,"Source":"Fontaine, C., & Galand, F. (2007). A survey of homomorphic encryption for nonspecialists. EURASIP Journal on Information Security, 2007, 1-10."},{"CategoryID":5,"Category":"Encryption and Decryption","Question":"This type of wallet stores a blockchain participant's private keys for accessing transaction without requiring a third party's storage capabilities.","Answer":"What is a Cold Wallet?","Value":800,"Source":"Cold Wallet. (n.d.). Ledger. Retrieved January 31, 2023, from https:\/\/www.ledger.com\/academy\/glossary\/cold-wallet#:~:text=The%20main%20function%20of%20cold"},{"CategoryID":5,"Category":"Encryption and Decryption","Question":"A type of public-key encryption where the public key is derived from a unique identifier, such as an email address, rather than a random value.","Answer":"What is Identity-Based Encryption?","Value":800,"Source":"Waters, B. (2005). Efficient identity-based encryption without random oracles. In Advances in Cryptology\u2013EUROCRYPT 2005: 24th Annual International Conference on the Theory and Applications of Cryptographic Techniques, Aarhus, Denmark, May 22-26, 2005. Proceedings 24 (pp. 114-127). Springer Berlin Heidelberg."},{"CategoryID":5,"Category":"Encryption and Decryption","Question":"This practice can be used in permissioned blockchain to perform sensitive computations on shared data without revealing the inputs of individual participants.","Answer":"What is Multi-Party Computation?","Value":1000,"Source":"Zhou, J., Feng, Y., Wang, Z., & Guo, D. (2021). Using secure multi-party computation to protect privacy on a permissioned blockchain. Sensors, 21(4), 1540."},{"CategoryID":5,"Category":"Encryption and Decryption","Question":"This type of cryptography is believed to be one of the only forms that is quantum-computer resistant due to its worst-case hardness","Answer":"What is Lattice-Based Cryptography?","Value":1000,"Source":"Micciancio, D., & Regev, O. (2009). Lattice-based cryptography. Post-quantum cryptography, 147-191."},{"CategoryID":6,"Category":"Foundations of Blockchain","Question":"This is a synonym for blockchain technology","Answer":"What is distributed ledger technology?","Value":200,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":6,"Category":"Foundations of Blockchain","Question":"One's access to data, including all digital property such as crypto currencies and or smart contracts is permanently lost if this is lost","Answer":"What is the private key?","Value":200,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":6,"Category":"Foundations of Blockchain","Question":"This component is part of a bitcoin network, is always sequential and permanently stores transactional data.","Answer":"What is a Block?","Value":200,"Source":"Li, J., Wu, J., & Chen, L. (2018). Block-secure: Blockchain based scheme for secure P2P cloud storage. Information Sciences, 465, 219-231. https:\/\/doi.org\/10.1016\/j.ins.2018.06.071"},{"CategoryID":6,"Category":"Foundations of Blockchain","Question":"Blocks are chained together using this cryptographical procedure.","Answer":"What is hashing?","Value":200,"Source":"Dorri, A., Kanhere, S. S., & Jurdak, R. (2016). Blockchain in internet of things: Challenges and Solutions. ArXiv. https:\/\/doi.org\/10.48550\/arXiv.1608.05187"},{"CategoryID":6,"Category":"Foundations of Blockchain","Question":"This is a blockchain that is run by a group  making them faster and scalable as the group dedicates the validation of the transactions.","Answer":"What Is Federated Blockchain?","Value":400,"Source":"Gondek, C. (n.d.). Public vs. Consortium vs. Federated vs. Private blockchain. Retrieved 30 January 2023, from https:\/\/originstamp.com\/blog\/public-consortium-private-blockchain\/"},{"CategoryID":6,"Category":"Foundations of Blockchain","Question":"This is the new type of decentralized monetary system that uses public blockchains like Ethereum as the underlying technology","Answer":"What is Decentralized Financed Technology?","Value":400,"Source":"Chen, Y., & Bellavitis, C. (2020). Blockchain disruption and decentralized finance: The rise of decentralized business models. Journal of Business Venturing Insights, 13, e00151."},{"CategoryID":6,"Category":"Foundations of Blockchain","Question":"This is a fundamental flaw in a digital cash protocol in which the same single digital token can be spent more than once. ","Answer":"What is double spending?","Value":600,"Source":"Karame, G. O., Androulaki, E., & Capkun, S. (2012). Double-spending fast payments in bitcoin. Proceedings of the 2012 ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security, 906\u2013917. https:\/\/doi.org\/10.1145\/2382196.2382292"},{"CategoryID":6,"Category":"Foundations of Blockchain","Question":"The is the method of gaining consensus on a change of data over the system or distributed network.","Answer":"What is a consensus algorithm?","Value":600,"Source":"Chaudhry, N., & Yousaf, M. M. (2018, December). Consensus algorithms in blockchain: Comparative analysis, challenges and opportunities. In\u00a02018 12th International Conference on Open Source Systems and Technologies (ICOSST)\u00a0(pp. 54-63). IEEE."},{"CategoryID":6,"Category":"Foundations of Blockchain","Question":"This ciphertext policy provides fine-grained access controls to achieve secure data sharing.","Answer":"What is Ciphertext-policy attribute-based encryption","Value":800,"Source":"S. Gao, G. Piao, J. Zhu, X. Ma and J. Ma, (2020) \"TrustAccess: A Trustworthy Secure Ciphertext-Policy and Attribute Hiding Access Control Scheme Based on Blockchain,\" in IEEE Transactions on Vehicular Technology, vol. 69, no. 6, pp. 5784-5798, June 2020, doi: 10.1109\/TVT.2020.2967099."},{"CategoryID":6,"Category":"Foundations of Blockchain","Question":"This feature works by asking nodes to provide proof of their work by providing the necessary computation power to solve tough mathematical puzzles.","Answer":"What is a Proof-Of-Work Consensus Algorithm?","Value":800,"Source":"Lasla, N., Al-Sahan, L., Abdallah, M., & Younis, M. (2022). Green-PoW: An energy-efficient blockchain proof-of-work consensus algorithm.\u00a0Computer Networks,\u00a0214, 109118."},{"CategoryID":6,"Category":"Foundations of Blockchain","Question":"This is the first transaction in a block. It is a unique type of bitcoin transaction that can be created by a miner.","Answer":"What is a Coinbase transaction?","Value":800,"Source":"McGinn, D., Birch, D., Akroyd, D., Molina-Solana, M., Guo, Y., & Knottenbelt, W. J. (2016). Visualizing dynamic bitcoin transaction patterns.\u00a0Big data,\u00a04(2), 109-119."},{"CategoryID":6,"Category":"Foundations of Blockchain","Question":"This refers to a miner or a group of miners who are trying to control more than 50% of a network's mining power, computing power or hash rate.","Answer":"What is a 51% attack?","Value":1000,"Source":"Aponte-Novoa, F. A., Orozco, A. L. S., Villanueva-Polanco, R., & Wightman, P. (2021). The 51% attack on blockchains: A mining behavior study.\u00a0IEEE Access,\u00a09, 140549-140564."},{"CategoryID":6,"Category":"Foundations of Blockchain","Question":"This is the collective decision to upgrade, modify, or fundamentally change the code for a specific cryptocurrency.","Answer":"What is a fork?","Value":1000,"Source":"Webb, N. (2018). A fork in the blockchain: income tax and the bitcoin\/bitcoin cash hard fork. North Carolina Journal of Law & Technology, 19(4), 283."},{"CategoryID":1,"Category":"Hashing Techniques","Question":"The process of using a one-way mathematical algorithm against data to produce a numeric value that is representative of that data","Answer":"What is hashing?","Value":200,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":1,"Category":"Hashing Techniques","Question":"This hashing algorithm has been considered to be insecure since 2008 due to cryptographic weakness","Answer":"What is MD5?","Value":200,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":1,"Category":"Hashing Techniques","Question":"This fixed-size bit string represents a message or a data set and is the output of a cryptographic hash function. It serves as a digital \"fingerprint\" for the input.","Answer":"What is a hash digest?","Value":200,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":1,"Category":"Hashing Techniques","Question":"This can occur when a hashing algorithm produces the same output for different inputs","Answer":"What is a hash collision?","Value":200,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":1,"Category":"Hashing Techniques","Question":"Since 2012, this is currently considered one of the most secure hashing algorithms in this generation","Answer":"What is SHA3?","Value":200,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":1,"Category":"Hashing Techniques","Question":"This value is typically easy-to-read and understand prior to being fed into a hash function","Answer":"What is a pre-image?","Value":400,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":1,"Category":"Hashing Techniques","Question":"The family of hashing functions that have been published by NIST as a U.S. Federal Processing Standards","Answer":"What is SHA?","Value":400,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":1,"Category":"Hashing Techniques","Question":"This type of hashing function uses a key that is known to both the sender and the receiver of the message","Answer":"What is a keyed hashed function?","Value":400,"Source":"Cherckesova, Safaryan, O. A., Lyashenko, N. G., & Korochentsev, D. A. (2022). Developing a New Collision-Resistant Hashing Algorithm.\u00a0Mathematics (Basel),\u00a010(15), 2769\u2013. https:\/\/doi.org\/10.3390\/math10152769"},{"CategoryID":1,"Category":"Hashing Techniques","Question":"In this tree, every \"leaf\" is labelled with crytographic hash","Answer":"What is a Merkle tree?","Value":400,"Source":"Buchmann, J., Dahmen, E. & Schneider, M. (1998) Merkle Tree Traversal Revisited. Part of the Lecture Notes in Computer Science book series (LNSC,volume 5299). Springer-Verlag Berlin Heidelberg "},{"CategoryID":1,"Category":"Hashing Techniques","Question":"This property of cryptographic hash functions ensures that it is computationally infeasible to find two distinct inputs that produce the same output.","Answer":"What is Hash Collision Resistance?","Value":600,"Source":"Holmgren, J., & Lombardi, A. (2018, October). Cryptographic hashing from strong one-way functions (or: One-way product functions and their applications). In 2018 IEEE 59th annual symposium on Foundations of Computer Science (FOCS) (pp. 850-858). IEEE."},{"CategoryID":1,"Category":"Hashing Techniques","Question":"This property of cryptographic hash functions ensures that it is computationally infeasible to find any input that produces a specific output.","Answer":"What is Pre-image Resistance?","Value":600,"Source":"Editor, C. C. (n.d.). Preimage resistance\u2014Glossary | csrc. Retrieved 31 January 2023, from https:\/\/csrc.nist.gov\/glossary\/term\/Preimage_resistance"},{"CategoryID":1,"Category":"Hashing Techniques","Question":"This behavior of a hash function ensures that a small change in the input should result in a significant change in the output.","Answer":"What is the Avalanche effect?","Value":600,"Source":"Demonstrate the avalanche effect of a hash function: New in wolfram language 12. (n.d.). Retrieved 31 January 2023, from https:\/\/www.wolfram.com\/language\/12\/cryptography\/demonstrate-the-avalanche-effect-of-a-hash-function.html"},{"CategoryID":1,"Category":"Hashing Techniques","Question":"This technique converts a large input value into a smaller hash value by dividing it into several equal-size pieces and adding them together to produce the hash value.","Answer":"What is the folding method?","Value":800,"Source":"Singh, M., & Garg, D. (2009, March). Choosing best hashing strategies and hash functions. In\u00a02009 IEEE International Advance Computing Conference\u00a0(pp. 50-55). IEEE."},{"CategoryID":1,"Category":"Hashing Techniques","Question":"This method of selecting a hash function at random from a family of hash functions with a certain mathematical property, such that the probability of a collision is small.","Answer":"What is Universal hashing?","Value":800,"Source":"Black, J., Halevi, S., Krawczyk, H., Krovetz, T., & Rogaway, P. (1999). UMAC: Fast and secure message authentication. In Advances in Cryptology\u2014CRYPTO\u201999: 19th Annual International Cryptology Conference Santa Barbara, California, USA, August 15\u201319, 1999 Proceedings 19 (pp. 216-233). Springer Berlin Heidelberg."},{"CategoryID":1,"Category":"Hashing Techniques","Question":"This data structure maps keys to values and uses a hash function to compute an index into an array of buckets, where each bucket is a linked list of key-value pairs.","Answer":"What is a Hash Table?","Value":1000,"Source":"Singh, M., & Garg, D. (2009, March). Choosing best hashing strategies and hash functions. In\u00a02009 IEEE International Advance Computing Conference\u00a0(pp. 50-55). IEEE."},{"CategoryID":1,"Category":"Hashing Techniques","Question":"This is when each binary digit (bit) of the ciphertext should depend on several parts of the key, obscuring the connections between the two","Answer":"What is confusion?","Value":1000,"Source":"Confusion and Diffusion in cryptography. (2020, December 6). Educate. https:\/\/educatech.in\/confusion-and-diffusion-in-cryptography\/"},{"CategoryID":12,"Category":"Integrity","Question":"The property that stored data is immutable and permanent, it cannot be modified or deleted.","Answer":"What is blockchain integrity?","Value":200,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":12,"Category":"Integrity","Question":"This cryptographic technique is used to chain blocks together in order to maintain order and integrity of blockchain networks.","Answer":"What is hashing?","Value":200,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":12,"Category":"Integrity","Question":"In this tree, every \"leaf\" is labelled with cryptographic hash. Every block stores transaction data in the form of a tree.","Answer":"What is Merkle Tree?","Value":400,"Source":"Hasib, H. (2019) Blockchain & Data Integrity https:\/\/medium.com\/@hmishfer17\/blockchain-data-integrity-e70e17cac086"},{"CategoryID":12,"Category":"Integrity","Question":"This is a characteristic of many blockchains where once data is added to the blockchain, it cannot be altered or deleted.","Answer":"What is immutability?","Value":400,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":12,"Category":"Integrity","Question":"These commonly used forms of signatures are mathematical ways of verifying the integrity of a message or document. Often used in blockchain networks to for providing authenticity of transactions.","Answer":"What is a digital signature?","Value":600,"Source":"Understanding digital signatures | cisa. (n.d.). Retrieved 31 January 2023, from https:\/\/www.cisa.gov\/uscert\/ncas\/tips\/ST04-018"},{"CategoryID":12,"Category":"Integrity","Question":"This is a cryptographic technique that is used to join two or more digital signatures. These combinations of digital signatures would provide a unique and valid digital signature for a document or digital information","Answer":"What is Signature Aggregation?","Value":600,"Source":"What is Signature Aggregation?. (n.d.). bit2me Academy. https:\/\/academy.bit2me.com\/en\/que-es-signature-aggregation\/"},{"CategoryID":12,"Category":"Integrity","Question":"This cryptographic technique can be used for running a lottery on a blockchain, to prevent miners from attempting to manipulate hashes to win the lottery","Answer":"What is a Verifiable Delay Function?","Value":800,"Source":"Fern\u00e0ndez-Val\u00e8ncia, R. (2021, June 22). Verifiable Delay Functions. Innovation Stories. https:\/\/medium.com\/iovlabs-innovation-stories\/verifiable-delay-functions-8eb6390c5f4"},{"CategoryID":12,"Category":"Integrity","Question":"This signature scheme is a cryptographic primitive for distributed key generation and signing.  It uses multi-party computation techniques to generate multiple public keys for a group of blockchain nodes based on a single private key","Answer":"What is the Threshold Signature Scheme?","Value":800,"Source":"Shlomovits O., Threshold Signatures Explained. (n.d.). Binance Academy. https:\/\/academy.binance.com\/en\/articles\/threshold-signatures-explained"},{"CategoryID":12,"Category":"Integrity","Question":"This mechanism can be used in blockchain networks to reach consensus to maintain integrity even in the presence of malicious or `faulty` participants.","Answer":"What is the Byzantine Fault Tolerance?","Value":1000,"Source":"Daly, L. (n.d.). What Is Byzantine Fault Tolerance? The Motley Fool. Retrieved January 31, 2023, from https:\/\/www.fool.com\/investing\/stock-market\/market-sectors\/financials\/cryptocurrency-stocks\/byzantine-fault-tolerance\/#:~:text=Byzantine%20Fault%20Tolerance%20is%20a"},{"CategoryID":12,"Category":"Integrity","Question":"These type of digital signature is a one-time signature scheme due to its design where private keys are released for verification. It works by computing multiple hashes of the message and combining those hashes to create the signature.","Answer":"What is a Lamport Signature?","Value":1000,"Source":"Abdullah, G. M., Mehmood, Q., & Khan, C. B. A. (2018, March). Adoption of Lamport signature scheme to implement digital signatures in IoT. In 2018 International conference on computing, mathematics and engineering technologies (iCoMET) (pp. 1-4). IEEE."},{"CategoryID":4,"Category":"Its Secret ","Question":"A feature of a protocol that ensure that session keys cannot be discovered after a private key is compromised","Answer":"What is Forward Secrecy?","Value":200,"Source":"Nikooghadam, & Amintoosi, H. (2020). Perfect forward secrecy via an ECC-based authentication scheme for SIP in VoIP. The Journal of Supercomputing, 76(4), 3086\u20133104. https:\/\/doi.org\/10.1007\/s11227-019-03086-z"},{"CategoryID":4,"Category":"Its Secret ","Question":"This kind of key is used in symmetric and asymmetric encryption schemes, typically used to encrypt and decrypt messages for confidentiality or integrity","Answer":"What is a private key?","Value":200,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":4,"Category":"Its Secret ","Question":"This type of key is used mainly in asymmetric encryption schemes, it is typically known by all parties and provide confidentiality as well as integrity if used correctly.","Answer":"What is a public key?","Value":200,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":4,"Category":"Its Secret ","Question":"This is the process of obfuscating passwords by introducing an arbitrary value to them after they\u2019ve been hashed.","Answer":"What is salting?","Value":200,"Source":"What does password salting do to protect against bad actors? (n.d.). Security. Retrieved 29 January 2023, from https:\/\/www.techtarget.com\/searchsecurity\/definition\/salt"},{"CategoryID":4,"Category":"Its Secret ","Question":"This security notion in cryptography states that an encryption scheme is secure if an attacker cannot tell which plaintext was encrypted, even if the attacker can ask for decryption of arbitrary ciphertexts.","Answer":"What is IND-CCA2?","Value":400,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":4,"Category":"Its Secret ","Question":"This technique tests the realness or integrity of a message. It is typically sent along with a copy of the message.","Answer":"What is a Message Authentication Code?","Value":400,"Source":"Editor, C. C. (n.d.). Message authentication code (Mac)\u2014Glossary | csrc. Retrieved 31 January 2023, from https:\/\/csrc.nist.gov\/glossary\/term\/message_authentication_code"},{"CategoryID":4,"Category":"Its Secret ","Question":"This is named after the surprise finding that the likelihood of two or more persons in a group of 23 sharing the same birthdate is more than 1\/2.","Answer":"What is the birthday paradox?","Value":400,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":4,"Category":"Its Secret ","Question":"This principle in cryptography states that a cryptosystem should be secure even if everything about the system, except the key, is public knowledge.","Answer":"What is Kerckhoffs' principle?","Value":400,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":4,"Category":"Its Secret ","Question":"This layer of  technology prevents eavesdropping or intercepting communication over the Internet","Answer":"What is transport layer security?","Value":400,"Source":"S. Turner, \"Transport Layer Security,\" in IEEE Internet Computing, vol. 18, no. 6, pp. 60-63, Nov.-Dec. 2014, doi: 10.1109\/MIC.2014.126."},{"CategoryID":4,"Category":"Its Secret ","Question":"This 12 to 24 secret word phrase serves as a backup for a blockchain wallet, allowing you to regain access to your funds if you lose your device or password.","Answer":"What is a seed phrase?","Value":600,"Source":"Deer, M. (2022, April 21). What is a seed phrase? https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/learn\/what-is-a-seed-phrase\/"},{"CategoryID":4,"Category":"Its Secret ","Question":"This type of blockchain network is designed to remain secret by controlling who has access to the network and the information stored on it. Typically the network is restricted to a pre-approved group of individuals.","Answer":"What is a private blockchain?","Value":600,"Source":"A comprehensive guide on private blockchains -. (2021, March 18). https:\/\/www.blockchain-council.org\/blockchain\/a-comprehensive-guide-on-private-blockchains\/"},{"CategoryID":4,"Category":"Its Secret ","Question":"An ideology of a perfectly secret encryption scheme, this theorem states that perfect secrecy comes from a truly randomly chosen key that produces a collision-free ciphertext when encrypting a plaintext.","Answer":"What is Shannon's Theorem?","Value":600,"Source":"Katz, J., & Lindell, Y. (2020). Introduction to modern cryptography. CRC press."},{"CategoryID":4,"Category":"Its Secret ","Question":"This type of node requires approval from a private blockchain network to participate and validate transactions that occur within it.","Answer":"What is a permissioned node?","Value":800,"Source":"Davenport, A., Shetty, S., & Liang, X. (2018, September). Attack surface analysis of permissioned blockchain platforms for smart cities. In 2018 IEEE International Smart Cities Conference (ISC2) (pp. 1-6). IEEE."},{"CategoryID":4,"Category":"Its Secret ","Question":"This cryptographic technique divides a secret into multiple parts called shares and distributes them among a group of participants, allowing the secret to be reconstructed if a sufficient number of shares are combined.","Answer":"What is Shamir Secret Sharing?","Value":800,"Source":"Stathakopoulou, C., & Cachin, C. (2017). Threshold signatures for blockchain systems. Swiss Federal Institute of Technology, 30, 1."},{"CategoryID":4,"Category":"Its Secret ","Question":"This cryptocurrency uses a process called zk-SNARKs to maintain anonymity in the blockchain network by not revealing anything about transaction except its validity.","Answer":"What is Zcash?","Value":800,"Source":"Zhang, Z., Li, W., Liu, H., & Liu, J. (2020). A refined analysis of zcash anonymity. Ieee Access, 8, 31845-31853."},{"CategoryID":4,"Category":"Its Secret ","Question":"Users on blockchain networks will sometimes perform this type of transaction in order to remain private, difficult-to-trace, and not publically visible.","Answer":"What is an off-chain transaction?","Value":800,"Source":"Xu, C., Zhang, C., Xu, J., & Pei, J. (2021). Slimchain: Scaling blockchain transactions through off-chain storage and parallel processing. Proceedings of the VLDB Endowment, 14(11), 2314-2326."},{"CategoryID":4,"Category":"Its Secret ","Question":"This cryptographic technique combines the shares of multiple participants to create digital signatures, providing increased security and scalability in blockchain systems.","Answer":"What are threshold signatures?","Value":1000,"Source":"Stathakopoulou, C., & Cachin, C. (2017). Threshold signatures for blockchain systems. Swiss Federal Institute of Technology, 30, 1."},{"CategoryID":4,"Category":"Its Secret ","Question":"This cryptographic protocol allows a sender to send a message to a receiver, without the sender knowing which message was actually received.","Answer":"What is the Oblivious Transfer protocol?","Value":1000,"Source":"Partala. (2017). Symmetric Blind Decryption with Perfect Secrecy. Journal of Computer Networks and Communications, 2017, 1\u201315. https:\/\/doi.org\/10.1155\/2017\/6575907"},{"CategoryID":3,"Category":"Private-Key Cryptography","Question":"A type of encryption that uses a secret key only once and is considered perfectly secure, if used correctly.","Answer":"What is a one time pad?","Value":200,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":3,"Category":"Private-Key Cryptography","Question":"Private keys are typically used for signing these in a blockchain network.","Answer":"What is a transaction?","Value":200,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":3,"Category":"Private-Key Cryptography","Question":"This is one of the biggest challenges with having a perfectly secret symmetric key cryptography scheme due to lack of secure channels to communicate keys.","Answer":"What is key distribution?","Value":400,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":3,"Category":"Private-Key Cryptography","Question":"These self-executing blockchain agreements can be executed using private keys that are authorized to perform under certain conditions.","Answer":"What are smart contracts?","Value":400,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":3,"Category":"Private-Key Cryptography","Question":"This type of attack in cryptography involves having access to both a message encrypted by a private key and a piece of the original message.","Answer":"What is a known plaintext attack?","Value":600,"Source":"Crypto-it. (n.d.). Retrieved 31 January 2023, from http:\/\/www.crypto-it.net\/eng\/attacks\/known-plaintext.html"},{"CategoryID":3,"Category":"Private-Key Cryptography","Question":"This term refers to the generation of truly unpredictable and unbiased numbers used as inputs to produce private keys.","Answer":"What is true randomness?","Value":600,"Source":"Skorski, M. (2014). On Recent Advances in Key Derivation via the Leftover Hash Lemma. In 2014 Imperial College Computing Student Workshop. Schloss Dagstuhl-Leibniz-Zentrum fuer Informatik."},{"CategoryID":3,"Category":"Private-Key Cryptography","Question":"This value is used as a starting point to generate a sequence of numbers that are used as private keys to secure sensitive information.","Answer":"What is a seed?","Value":800,"Source":"Learn all about seed phrases in 5 minutes | worldcoin. (n.d.). Retrieved 31 January 2023, from https:\/\/worldcoin.org\/articles\/what-is-seed-phrase"},{"CategoryID":3,"Category":"Private-Key Cryptography","Question":"Designed by IBM in the 70s, this private key encryption scheme was the gold standard for commercial and unclassified government applications, before being deemed as insecure in the 90s.","Answer":"What is DES?","Value":800,"Source":"Kessler, G. C. (2003). An Overview of Cryptography."},{"CategoryID":3,"Category":"Private-Key Cryptography","Question":"This technical specification in the Bitcoin ecosystem defines the structure of hierarchical deterministic wallets and the rules for generating private keys from a seed phrase.","Answer":"What is BIP-32?","Value":1000,"Source":"Yu, G. (2020). Blockchain stealth address schemes. Cryptology ePrint Archive ."},{"CategoryID":3,"Category":"Private-Key Cryptography","Question":"This type of cryptographic wallet uses a hierarchical structure and a deterministic algorithm to generate an unlimited number of private keys from a single seed phrase. ","Answer":"What is a Hierarchical Deterministic wallet?","Value":1000,"Source":"Yu, G. (2020). Blockchain stealth address schemes. Cryptology ePrint Archive ."},{"CategoryID":2,"Category":"Public-Key Cryptography","Question":"This method of verifying the authenticity of a message or document using a pair of keys, one for signing and one for verifying, and it is used in various applications such as email, file transfer, software distribution and e-commerce.","Answer":"What is a Digital Signature?","Value":200,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":2,"Category":"Public-Key Cryptography","Question":"This is a public key cryptography approach that is based on encryption, as well as authentication. It was first used in the year 1977 and is based on prime number logic.","Answer":"What is RSA?","Value":200,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":2,"Category":"Public-Key Cryptography","Question":"This trusted third-party organization issues digital certificates that bind a public key to an identity as well as verify the identity of certificate holders.","Answer":"What is Certificate Authority?","Value":200,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":2,"Category":"Public-Key Cryptography","Question":"This public-key cryptosystem, proposed by Taher ElGamal in 1985, is based on the mathematical problem of computing discrete logarithms and is often used for encryption and digital signatures.","Answer":"What is the El Gamel cryptosystem?","Value":400,"Source":"Partala. (2017). Symmetric Blind Decryption with Perfect Secrecy. Journal of Computer Networks and Communications, 2017, 1\u201315. https:\/\/doi.org\/10.1155\/2017\/6575907"},{"CategoryID":2,"Category":"Public-Key Cryptography","Question":"This list of digital certificates that have been revoked by a Certification Authority (CA) before their scheduled expiration date. Used to ensure that a certificate that has been compromised or is no longer valid.","Answer":"What is Certificate Revocation List?","Value":400,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":2,"Category":"Public-Key Cryptography","Question":"This Internet protocol is used to determine the revocation status of a digital certificate, as an alternative method to the Certificate Revocation Lists (CRLs).","Answer":"What is Online Certificate Status Protocol?","Value":400,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":2,"Category":"Public-Key Cryptography","Question":"This approach to public-key cryptography is based on the algebraic properties of elliptic curves and provides the same level of security with smaller key sizes, making it more efficient for use in devices with limited resources.","Answer":"What is Elliptic Curve Cryptography?","Value":600,"Source":"Bos, J. W., Halderman, J. A., Heninger, N., Moore, J., Naehrig, M., & Wustrow, E. (2014). Elliptic curve cryptography in practice. In Financial Cryptography and Data Security: 18th International Conference, FC 2014, Christ Church, Barbados, March 3-7, 2014, Revised Selected Papers 18 (pp. 157-175). Springer Berlin Heidelberg."},{"CategoryID":2,"Category":"Public-Key Cryptography","Question":"Blockchain networks use public key cryptography to generate these unique identifiers that represent an entity in a transaction.","Answer":"What is a wallet address?","Value":600,"Source":"Doran, M. D. (2014). A forensic look at bitcoin cryptocurrency (Doctoral dissertation, Utica College)."},{"CategoryID":2,"Category":"Public-Key Cryptography","Question":"This set of standards, policies, procedures, and technologies are used to establish and maintain a secure communication channel by providing a secure method for exchanging public keys.","Answer":"What is Public Key Infrastructure?","Value":800,"Source":"What is public key infrastructure (Pki) & how does it work? | okta. (n.d.). Retrieved 31 January 2023, from https:\/\/www.okta.com\/identity-101\/public-key-infrastructure\/"},{"CategoryID":2,"Category":"Public-Key Cryptography","Question":"This standard for digital signatures developed by NIST, which specifies a set of algorithms and procedures for creating and verifying digital signatures and is widely used to secure sensitive data.","Answer":"What is the Digital Signature Standard?","Value":1000,"Source":"El Sobky, W., Hamdy, S., & Mohamed, M. H. (2021). Elliptic curve digital signature algorithm challenges and development stages. Int. J. Innov. Technol. Exploring Eng., 10(10), 121-128."},{"CategoryID":2,"Category":"Public-Key Cryptography","Question":"This is an asymmetric block key encryption that is efficient yet demands pre-processing equivalent","Answer":"What is a blowfish?","Value":1000,"Source":"Schneier on security: The blowfish encryption algorithm. (n.d.). Retrieved 29 January 2023, from https:\/\/www.schneier.com\/academic\/blowfish\/"},{"CategoryID":2,"Category":"Public-Key Cryptography","Question":"This is a database protocol used for the updating and searching of the directories which run over the TCP\/IP network protocol and typically uses PKI.","Answer":"What is Lightweight Directory Access Protocol?","Value":1000,"Source":"REDMOND\\\\markl. (n.d.). Lightweight directory access protocol. Retrieved 29 January 2023, from https:\/\/learn.microsoft.com\/en-us\/previous-versions\/windows\/desktop\/ldap\/lightweight-directory-access-protocol-ldap-api"},{"CategoryID":7,"Category":"Smart Contracts","Question":"Smart contracts are a type of contract that are stored on a blockchain and typically run after meeting certain pre-established conditions. ","Answer":"what is digital?","Value":200,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":7,"Category":"Smart Contracts","Question":"Smart contracts are used to automate the execution of an agreement allowing for all participants to immediately see the outcome without third-party involvement and without any time loss.  This can be automate to trigger the next action when conditions are met. ","Answer":"What are workflows?","Value":200,"Source":"ISEC 601 Applied Cryptography - Winter Semester 2023"},{"CategoryID":7,"Category":"Smart Contracts","Question":"This type of smart contact try's to solve a software management problem using crypto technology that aims at managing decentralized open source technology by design.","Answer":"What is a DAO?","Value":400,"Source":"Wright, A. (21021) \"The rise of decentralized autonomous organizations: Opportunities and challenges.\" Stanford Journal of Blockchain Law & Policy 4.2 (2021): 152-176."},{"CategoryID":7,"Category":"Smart Contracts","Question":"These contracts are legally enforceable and require the parties to satisfy their contractual obligations. Parties may face strict legal actions if they fail to comply","Answer":"What is a Smart Legal Contract?","Value":400,"Source":"Smart contracts in blockchain: Types, use cases & more. (n.d.). Imaginovation | Top Web & Mobile App Development Company Raleigh. Retrieved January 31, 2023, from https:\/\/imaginovation.net\/blog\/smart-contracts-in-blockchain\/"},{"CategoryID":7,"Category":"Smart Contracts","Question":"The majority of smart contract programming is written in this type of programming language","Answer":"What is Object-oriented?","Value":400,"Source":"Smart contracts in blockchain: Types, use cases & more. (n.d.). Imaginovation | Top Web & Mobile App Development Company Raleigh. Retrieved January 31, 2023, from https:\/\/imaginovation.net\/blog\/smart-contracts-in-blockchain\/"},{"CategoryID":7,"Category":"Smart Contracts","Question":"These smart contracts contain an application-based code, which typically remains in sync with other blockchain contracts. It enables communication across different devices, such as the Internet of Things (IoT) merger with blockchain technology. ","Answer":"What are Application Logic Contracts?","Value":600,"Source":"Smart contracts in blockchain: Types, use cases & more. (n.d.). Imaginovation | Top Web & Mobile App Development Company Raleigh. Retrieved January 31, 2023, from https:\/\/imaginovation.net\/blog\/smart-contracts-in-blockchain\/"},{"CategoryID":7,"Category":"Smart Contracts","Question":"During the four (4) phases of a smart contracts lifecycle (Creation, Deployment, Execution & Completion), this is the only phase that does not need to write data to the block chain.","Answer":"What is the Creation Phase?","Value":600,"Source":"Smart contracts in blockchain: Types, use cases & more. (n.d.). Imaginovation | Top Web & Mobile App Development Company Raleigh. Retrieved January 31, 2023, from https:\/\/imaginovation.net\/blog\/smart-contracts-in-blockchain\/"},{"CategoryID":7,"Category":"Smart Contracts","Question":"This type of smart contract may encounter the following governance issues; Procedural tedium, legal indeterminacy governance, and or voter manipulation","Answer":"What is a DAO?","Value":800,"Source":"Zwitter A, Hazenberg J (2020) Decentralized Network Governance: Blockchain Technology and the Future of Regulation. Front. Blockchain 3:12. doi: 10.3389\/fbloc.2020.00012"},{"CategoryID":7,"Category":"Smart Contracts","Question":"Smart contracts can bring benefits to IoT e-business model. For example, the traditional e-business model often requires a third party serving as an agent to complete the payment. However, this centralized payment is costly and cannot fully utilize advantages of IoT. These were proposed to automate transactions, in which there are no traditional roles like governments or companies involved with the payment.","Answer":"What are Distributed autonomous Corporations (DACs)?","Value":800,"Source":"Zheng, Z., Xie, S., Dai, H.-N., Chen, W., Chen, X., Weng, J., & Imran, M. (2020). An overview on smart contracts: Challenges, advances and platforms. Future Generation Computer Systems, 105, 475\u2013491. https:\/\/doi.org\/10.1016\/j.future.2019.12.019"},{"CategoryID":7,"Category":"Smart Contracts","Question":"This intermediate level language with similar syntax to Low level Virtual Language (LLVM) provides compilers with high-level information during the compile time, link time, run time, and idle time. Ultimately improving smart contract readability challenges, specifically human readability during the execution phase. ","Answer":"What is IELE?","Value":1000,"Source":"Zheng, Z., Xie, S., Dai, H.-N., Chen, W., Chen, X., Weng, J., & Imran, M. (2020). An overview on smart contracts: Challenges, advances and platforms. Future Generation Computer Systems, 105, 475\u2013491. https:\/\/doi.org\/10.1016\/j.future.2019.12.019"},{"CategoryID":7,"Category":"Smart Contracts","Question":"This is a decentralised smart contract system that maintains transactional privacy by not storing financial transactions on the blockchain in the publics view. The compiler automatically creates an effective cryptographic protocol where contractual parties interact with the blockchain using cryptographic primitives like zero-knowledge proofs, so a programmer does not need to implement cryptography in order to create a private smart contract.","Answer":"What is Hawk?","Value":1000,"Source":"Kosba, A., Miller, A., Shi, E., Wen, Z., & Papamanthou, C. (2016). Hawk: The blockchain model of cryptography and privacy-preserving smart contracts. 2016 IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (SP), 839\u2013858. https:\/\/doi.org\/10.1109\/SP.2016.55"}]}
